<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Jing&#39;s blog</title>
  
  
  <link href="http://example.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://example.com/"/>
  <updated>2023-02-20T01:18:45.314Z</updated>
  <id>http://example.com/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Jing</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>用ChatGPT写课程大纲</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2023/02/18/Syllabus-chatGPT/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2023/02/18/Syllabus-chatGPT/</id>
    <published>2023-02-18T02:06:07.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-02-20T01:18:45.314Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>让ChatGPT 写了6门课的课程大纲，这里展示其中1门课。</p><span id="more"></span><p><em>Course Title: Information Visualization: Designing Effective and Engaging Visualizations</em></p><p>Course Description: This course will introduce you to the principles and best practices of information visualization, and provide you with the tools and techniques you need to design effective and engaging visualizations for a variety of applications.</p><p>Course Goals:</p><p>-Understand the principles of information visualization<br>-Learn how to choose appropriate visualization techniques for different data types and tasks<br>-Develop skills in designing and implementing visualizations using software tools<br>-Evaluate the effectiveness and usability of visualizations</p><p>Course Outline:</p><p>I. Introduction to Information Visualization<br>-What is information visualization?<br>-The importance of effective visualization<br>-Overview of the course</p><p>II. Principles of Information Visualization<br>-Perception and cognition<br>-Visualization design principles<br>-Types of visualization techniques</p><p>III. Data Types and Visualization Techniques<br>-Visualizing hierarchical data<br>-Visualizing temporal and spatial data<br>-Visualizing network and graph data<br>-Visualizing multidimensional data</p><p>IV. Designing Effective Visualizations<br>-Defining visualization objectives and tasks<br>-Designing effective visualizations<br>-Choosing appropriate visual encoding techniques<br>-Tools and software for visualization design and development</p><p>V. Evaluating and Testing Visualizations<br>-Principles of user-centered design<br>-Usability testing and evaluation<br>-Cognitive walkthroughs and heuristic evaluation<br>-Gathering feedback and iterating on design</p><p>VI. Advanced Topics in Information Visualization<br>-Interactive visualizations and dashboards<br>-Visualization for machine learning and AI applications<br>-Visualization for scientific and engineering data<br>-Ethical considerations in visualization design and use</p><p>VII. Practicing Visualization Design Skills<br>-Visualization design exercises and assignments<br>-Group projects and presentations<br>-Feedback and evaluation</p><p>Course Requirements:<br>-Regular attendance and participation in class<br>-Completion of assigned readings and exercises<br>-Active engagement in discussions and group projects<br>-Final project and presentation</p><p>Assessment:<br>-Class participation and engagement: 20%<br>-Assignments and exercises: 30%<br>-Group project and presentation: 30%<br>-Final project and presentation: 20%</p><p>This is just one possible outline for a course on information visualization. Depending on the target audience and course objectives, other topics could be added or removed. The important thing is to provide students with the knowledge and skills they need to create effective and engaging visualizations for a wide range of applications.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;让ChatGPT 写了6门课的课程大纲，这里展示其中1门课。&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>用ChatGPT写Python代码</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2023/02/18/chatGPT-python/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2023/02/18/chatGPT-python/</id>
    <published>2023-02-18T02:06:07.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-02-20T00:54:48.329Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ask ChatGPT to  write some Python code. It seems to work well.</p><span id="more"></span><p><strong>Please write a simple code in Python</strong></p><p>ChatGPT</p><p>Sure, here’s an example of a simple Python program that takes a user’s name and age as input and prints a personalized greeting:</p><p>python<br>Copy code</p><figure class="highlight plaintext"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">&#123;</span><br><span class="line">name = input(&quot;What&#x27;s your name? &quot;)</span><br><span class="line">age = input(&quot;How old are you? &quot;)</span><br><span class="line">print(&quot;Hello, &quot; + name + &quot;! You&#x27;re &quot; + age + &quot; years old.&quot;)</span><br><span class="line">&#125;</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>In this program, the input function is used to prompt the user for their name and age, and the values entered by the user are stored in the name and age variables. The print function is then used to print a personalized greeting that includes the user’s name and age.</p><p>This is a very basic example, but it demonstrates some of the core concepts of Python programming, including variables, input&#x2F;output, and string manipulation. With these building blocks, you can go on to create more complex programs and applications in Python.</p><p><strong>Please write a piece of code to crawl data in Python</strong></p><p>ChatGPT</p><p>Sure! Here’s a simple example of Python code that uses the requests and BeautifulSoup libraries to crawl data from a web page and extract information from it:</p><p>python<br>Copy code</p><figure class="highlight plaintext"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br><span class="line">8</span><br><span class="line">9</span><br><span class="line">10</span><br><span class="line">11</span><br><span class="line">12</span><br><span class="line">13</span><br><span class="line">14</span><br><span class="line">15</span><br><span class="line">16</span><br><span class="line">17</span><br><span class="line">18</span><br><span class="line">19</span><br><span class="line">20</span><br><span class="line">21</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">&#123;</span><br><span class="line">import requests</span><br><span class="line">from bs4 import BeautifulSoup</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line"># Make a GET request to the target URL</span><br><span class="line">url = &#x27;https://www.example.com&#x27;</span><br><span class="line">response = requests.get(url)</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line"># Check the response status code to make sure the request was successful</span><br><span class="line">if response.status_code == 200:</span><br><span class="line">    # Parse the HTML content of the response using BeautifulSoup</span><br><span class="line">    soup = BeautifulSoup(response.content, &#x27;html.parser&#x27;)</span><br><span class="line">    </span><br><span class="line">    # Find all the links on the page and print their URLs</span><br><span class="line">    links = soup.find_all(&#x27;a&#x27;)</span><br><span class="line">    for link in links:</span><br><span class="line">        print(link.get(&#x27;href&#x27;))</span><br><span class="line">else:</span><br><span class="line">    # If the request was not successful, print an error message</span><br><span class="line">print(&#x27;Error: Could not retrieve data&#x27;)</span><br><span class="line">&#125;</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>In this example, we first import the requests and BeautifulSoup libraries, which are used to make HTTP requests and parse HTML content, respectively. We then make a GET request to a target URL using the requests.get() function and check the status code of the response to make sure the request was successful.</p><p>If the request was successful, we use BeautifulSoup to parse the HTML content of the response and find all the links on the page using the soup.find_all() method. We then loop through the list of links and print their URLs using the link.get(‘href’) method.</p><p>If the request was not successful, we print an error message to indicate that we were not able to retrieve the data.</p><p>This is just a simple example, but it demonstrates the basic structure of a Python web scraping script. Depending on the target website and the data you want to extract, you may need to use additional libraries or techniques to parse the content and extract the relevant information.</p><p><strong>Please write a piece of data visualization code in Python</strong></p><p>ChatGPT</p><p>Sure, here’s an example of a simple data visualization using the matplotlib library in Python:</p><p>python<br>Copy code</p><figure class="highlight plaintext"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br><span class="line">8</span><br><span class="line">9</span><br><span class="line">10</span><br><span class="line">11</span><br><span class="line">12</span><br><span class="line">13</span><br><span class="line">14</span><br><span class="line">15</span><br><span class="line">16</span><br><span class="line">17</span><br><span class="line">18</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">&#123;</span><br><span class="line">import matplotlib.pyplot as plt</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line"># Define the data to be plotted</span><br><span class="line">x_values = [1, 2, 3, 4, 5]</span><br><span class="line">y_values = [5, 3, 7, 2, 4]</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line"># Create a line chart of the data</span><br><span class="line">plt.plot(x_values, y_values)</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line"># Add a title and axis labels to the chart</span><br><span class="line">plt.title(&quot;Example Line Chart&quot;)</span><br><span class="line">plt.xlabel(&quot;X-axis Label&quot;)</span><br><span class="line">plt.ylabel(&quot;Y-axis Label&quot;)</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line"># Display the chart</span><br><span class="line">plt.show()</span><br><span class="line">&#125;</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>In this example, we first import the matplotlib.pyplot library and define the data to be plotted in the form of two lists: x_values and y_values.</p><p>We then use the plt.plot() function to create a line chart of the data, and the plt.title(), plt.xlabel(), and plt.ylabel() functions to add a title and axis labels to the chart.</p><p>Finally, we use the plt.show() function to display the chart on the screen.</p><p>This is just a simple example, but matplotlib provides a wide range of tools and customization options for creating more complex and detailed visualizations. With the right data and tools, you can create stunning and informative visualizations that help you gain insights and communicate your findings to others.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ask ChatGPT to  write some Python code. It seems to work well.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>人类最大的敌人是？看ChatGPT如何回答？</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2023/02/18/enemy/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2023/02/18/enemy/</id>
    <published>2023-02-18T02:06:07.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-02-20T01:28:01.553Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>问ChatGPT，人类最大的敌人是谁？它用英文回答，似乎比中文回答要好得多。如果这是一篇作文，你给它多少分？</p><span id="more"></span><p>The biggest enemy of human</p><blockquote><p>Humans have many enemies, but the biggest enemy of all is themselves.<br>Human beings have the capacity to create their own problems, and these problems can be caused by a variety of factors.<br>The most common enemy of humans is their own ignorance. Ignorance can lead to bad decisions, which can have long-term consequences. For example, people may not understand the consequences of their actions, such as the effects of pollution on the environment. Ignorance can also lead to prejudice, which can cause people to make unfair decisions based on false information or stereotypes.<br>Another enemy of humans is their own greed. Greed can lead people to pursue wealth and power at the expense of others. This can create an unequal society where the rich get richer and the poor get poorer. Greed can also lead to corruption, which can have serious consequences for society.<br>Finally, humans are their own worst enemy when it comes to their health. People often make poor choices when it comes to their diet and exercise, leading to health problems such as obesity and heart disease. People may also be exposed to dangerous chemicals or pollutants, leading to long-term health problems.</p></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;问ChatGPT，人类最大的敌人是谁？它用英文回答，似乎比中文回答要好得多。如果这是一篇作文，你给它多少分？&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>ChatGPT推荐了五个网页设计自学网站</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2023/02/18/html-study-chatGPT/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2023/02/18/html-study-chatGPT/</id>
    <published>2023-02-18T02:06:07.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-02-20T01:25:42.946Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>让ChatGPT 写HTML，它说还没有这个技能，但可以推荐自学网站。以下是它推荐的5个网站。</p><span id="more"></span><p><a href="https://www.w3schools.com/html">https://www.w3schools.com/html</a><br>This website provides comprehensive tutorials and references on HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and other web development technologies. It is a great resource for beginners who want to learn how to build web pages.</p><p><a href="https://www.codecademy.com/learn/learn-html">https://www.codecademy.com/learn/learn-html</a><br>Codecademy is an interactive online learning platform that offers courses on a variety of programming languages and web development technologies, including HTML. It provides a hands-on approach to learning, allowing you to practice coding as you learn.</p><p><a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Learn/HTML">https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Learn/HTML</a><br>The Mozilla Developer Network provides a wealth of resources and tutorials on web development, including HTML. It is a great resource for both beginners and advanced users who want to learn more about web development.</p><p><a href="https://html5up.net/">https://html5up.net</a><br>HTML5up is a website that provides free HTML templates that you can use to build your own web pages. These templates are designed to be responsive and easy to use, and can be a great starting point for building your own website.</p><p><a href="https://pages.github.com/">https://pages.github.com</a><br>GitHub Pages is a free web hosting service provided by GitHub. You can use it to host your own static web pages, including those built with HTML. It is a great way to get your web page online without having to pay for hosting.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;让ChatGPT 写HTML，它说还没有这个技能，但可以推荐自学网站。以下是它推荐的5个网站。&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>学生作业--搭建网站</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2023/02/11/student-web/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2023/02/11/student-web/</id>
    <published>2023-02-11T14:06:07.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-02-12T07:21:25.075Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Learn to set up personal website </p><span id="more"></span><p>马来西亚棕榈油<br><a href="https://leefamejie.github.io/malaysiapalmoil/index.html#features22-3y">https://leefamejie.github.io/malaysiapalmoil/index.html#features22-3y</a></p><p>新加坡公共住房<br><a href="https://shjshiny.github.io/sghome/">https://shjshiny.github.io/sghome/</a></p><p> 越南人口生育率<br><a href="https://rsmingyue.github.io/rsmingyue/index.html#header12-a2">https://rsmingyue.github.io/rsmingyue/index.html#header12-a2</a></p><p>疫情下的泰国旅游业<br><a href="https://zhengyzh666.github.io/tourismTH/index.html#header12-a2">https://zhengyzh666.github.io/tourismTH/index.html#header12-a2</a></p><p>在越南学汉语<br><a href="https://longli21.github.io/Hanoi-University/">https://longli21.github.io/Hanoi-University/</a></p><p>印尼旅游业<br><a href="https://chinnyparamita.github.io/">https://chinnyparamita.github.io/</a></p><p>表白墙<br><a href="https://xytan2000.github.io/bbqkeshihua/">https://xytan2000.github.io/bbqkeshihua/</a></p><p>碳中和<br><a href="https://china-carbon-neutrality.github.io/China-Carbon-Neutrality.html">https://china-carbon-neutrality.github.io/China-Carbon-Neutrality.html</a></p><p>个人简历<br><a href="https://bemen-cell.github.io/">https://bemen-cell.github.io</a><br><a href="https://liangjianqiang10.github.io/">https://liangjianqiang10.github.io/</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Learn to set up personal website &lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>在线引入flourish图表</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2021/12/20/flourish/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2021/12/20/flourish/</id>
    <published>2021-12-20T02:06:07.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-02-12T07:21:09.133Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>在网页中引入flourish图表</p><ul><li>注册<a href="https://flourish.studio/%EF%BC%8C%E5%AF%BC%E5%85%A5%E6%95%B0%E6%8D%AE%EF%BC%8C%E7%94%9F%E6%88%90%E5%9B%BE%E8%A1%A8">https://flourish.studio/，导入数据，生成图表</a></li><li>Export and publish，显示Embed on your website，复制代码</li><li>将复制的代码嵌入网页</li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;在网页中引入flourish图表&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;注册&lt;a href=&quot;https://flourish.studio/%EF%BC%8C%E5%AF%BC%E5%85%A5%E6%95%B0%E6%8D%AE%EF%BC%8C%E7%94%9F%E6%88%90</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>代码编辑器HBuilderX</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2021/12/18/code-editor/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2021/12/18/code-editor/</id>
    <published>2021-12-18T02:06:07.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-02-12T07:20:45.029Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>使用代码编辑器HBuilderX制作网页</p><p>HBuilderX，简称HX。 H是HTML的首字母，Builder是构造者，X是HBuilder的下一代版本。<br>HX既可以是编辑器，也可以是IDE（集成开发环境，使程序员能够整合编写计算机程序的不同方面）。</p><span id="more"></span><p>下载地址：<a href="https://www.dcloud.io/hbuilderx.html">https://www.dcloud.io/hbuilderx.html</a></p><p>支持java插件、nodejs插件，并兼容了很多vscode的插件及代码块。 还可以通过外部命令，方便地调用各种命令行功能，并设置快捷键。</p><p>可在网页里引入flourish、tableau、echarts在线数据图。</p><blockquote><p>[参见HX教程] (<a href="https://www.dcloud.io/hbuilderx.html">https://www.dcloud.io/hbuilderx.html</a>)</p></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;使用代码编辑器HBuilderX制作网页&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HBuilderX，简称HX。 H是HTML的首字母，Builder是构造者，X是HBuilder的下一代版本。&lt;br&gt;HX既可以是编辑器，也可以是IDE（集成开发环境，使程序员能够整合编写计算机程序的不同方面）。&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>词频分析</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2021/03/03/word-frequency/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2021/03/03/word-frequency/</id>
    <published>2021-03-03T02:22:45.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-02-12T07:17:05.919Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>自选文本进行词频分析练习，导出数据，生成词云图</p><span id="more"></span><p>1、查找数据：</p><blockquote><p>数据源：毛泽东的诗词全集、诗集(89首全)_诗词名句网 (shicimingju.com)</p></blockquote><!-- more --><p>2、爬取数据</p><blockquote><p>使用后羿采集器对网页进行爬取，爬取到毛泽东诗集89首</p></blockquote><p>3、清洗数据</p><blockquote><p>修改数据格式，将爬取的数据中的换行符、空格等删去</p></blockquote><p>4、python词频统计</p><blockquote><p>参见 <a href="https://blog.csdn.net/laobai1015/article/details/80420016">https://blog.csdn.net/laobai1015/article/details/80420016</a></p></blockquote><p>5、再次进行数据清洗</p><blockquote><p>对一些介词、单字进行删除</p></blockquote><p>6：导入词云图制作网址，制成词云图</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;自选文本进行词频分析练习，导出数据，生成词云图&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>在线引入Echarts地图遇到的问题</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2020/12/04/echarts-map/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2020/12/04/echarts-map/</id>
    <published>2020-12-04T02:06:07.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-02-12T07:20:56.628Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>在线地图不符合国家标准问题</p><p>在线引入Echarts地图，除了需要引入echarts.min.js，还需要引入china.js，但由于Echarts原有China地图不是国家标准地图，官方已经停用，因此引入Echarts地图会遇到问题。</p><span id="more"></span><p>另外，引入echarts.min.js时，在线引入经常由于在线链接的变化而导致链接失效，导致Echarts无法正常引入。建议下载最新版echarts.min.js，将其置于与index同一文件夹，这样只要写一句引入代码就可以了。</p><pre><code>&lt;script src=&quot;echarts.min.js&quot;&gt;</code></pre><blockquote><p>[参见Echarts教程] (<a href="https://echarts.apache.org/zh/tutorial.html">https://echarts.apache.org/zh/tutorial.html</a>)</p></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;在线地图不符合国家标准问题&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在线引入Echarts地图，除了需要引入echarts.min.js，还需要引入china.js，但由于Echarts原有China地图不是国家标准地图，官方已经停用，因此引入Echarts地图会遇到问题。&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>学习hexo</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2020/11/30/study/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2020/11/30/study/</id>
    <published>2020-11-30T14:06:07.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-02-20T01:15:04.872Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>菜鸟学习用hexo和github搭建主页</p><span id="more"></span><p>踩了无数坑，看了无数过时的经验贴，终于搞定了。<br>这些坑包括：没有在代码中间应该加空格的地方加空格，把- -（两条横杠）写成-（一条横杠），换Theme时的链接是过时无效的，无法生成模板，还在英文单词打错了…..</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;菜鸟学习用hexo和github搭建主页&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>master改为main的影响</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2020/11/30/master-to-main/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2020/11/30/master-to-main/</id>
    <published>2020-11-30T14:00:11.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-02-12T07:21:16.055Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>用hexo和github搭建个人博客踩的最大的坑<br>2020年10月1日起，在github上创建的任何新仓库都将使用main作为默认分支，而不是master。</p><span id="more"></span><p>因此，在hexo的_config里，要将以下代码做修改</p><blockquote><p>Deploy<br>  type: git<br>  repo: <a href="https://github.com/yourname/yourname.github.io.git">https://github.com/yourname/yourname.github.io.git</a><br>  branch: main</p></blockquote><blockquote><p>注意，branch以前是master，现在要改为main</p></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;用hexo和github搭建个人博客踩的最大的坑&lt;br&gt;2020年10月1日起，在github上创建的任何新仓库都将使用main作为默认分支，而不是master。&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
